JACKSON ROBBINS

jackson@jacksonr.com | (312) 429-7345 | www.linkedin.com/in/jacksonrobbins606 | jacksonr.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full stack web developer and literal "Jack of all trades." I have expertise from prior roles that encompass sales, marketing, operations, customer support, and most recently software development. From my extensive experience in customer facing roles, I am skilled at understanding the technology needs of customers or stakeholders and communicating solutions in simple and relatable terms. I am a lifelong learner who enjoys studying complex systems and solving problems.

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Working Knowledge: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, WordPress, PHP, Restful API Systems, SQL, Linux Ubuntu & CentOS, Ionic, Angular, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material Design Lite, Git, Node.js, FreshDesk, Trello, Invision, Google Suite

WORK EXPERIENCE

National Democratic Training Committee — Chicago, IL

August 2019 — Present

Web Developer

NDTC develops a free online and in-person learning platform to train the next generation of Democrats to run for office.

- Collaborate with NDTC's teams to design and build new features for <u>traindemocrats.org</u>.
- Follow product roadmap to develop improvements for our software built on WordPress.

AMOpportunities — Chicago, IL

July 2018 — November 2018

Junior Web Developer

AMO develops an online platform that connects healthcare providers with medical students seeking clinical rotations.

- Developed the front-end of AMO's web and mobile app using Ionic and Angular.
- Worked alongside AMO's various teams to gather input and design custom components for the app's UX / UI.

TouchBistro — Chicago, IL

July 2017 — October 2017

Customer Care Specialist

Toronto-based tech company that develops a restaurant point of sale (POS) system for the iPad.

- Handle Tier 1 customer support requests from inbound calls, emails, and tickets.
- Assist clients with account options, ongoing subscriptions / billing, and troubleshooting technical issues.
- Created documentation for the support team's procedures to improve the quality and consistency of customer service.

Personal Projects

Primal Portal — <u>Demo</u> | <u>Code</u>

Web portal for Chicago Primal Gym members to record and view their personal records with interactive dashboards.

- Built back end with Ruby on Rails set-up as a RESTFUL API and hosted on Heroku.
- Created front end with React and used Material-UI for styling the interface and React Router for user navigation.
- Generated interactive animated charts using Uber's react-vis library.
- Implemented secure login and user authentication using JSON web tokens and bcrypt.

Grumbler — **Code**

WebApp to search and view food inspection records for every Chicago restaurant.

- Utilized Google Cloud Services to enable users to find restaurants with a "Googly" search bar with relevant results.
- Used Chicago's Data Portal and Food Inspection Records API to show inspection records for Chicago restaurants.

D3 USA Map — Demo | Code

Straight forward example of using D3 to render a classic Albers projection of the U.S. with animated landmark pins

- Developed to dynamically render maps for the National Democratic Training Committee's site traindemocrats.org
- Built with D3 and GeoJSON data of the US. Map is made of vector images so it stays sharp at any size or zoom level.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School — Chicago, IL

April 2019 — July 2019

15 week full-time coding bootcamp that teaches full-stack web development

Macalester College — St. Paul, MN

August 2008 — May 2012

• Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology (GPA: 3.10)

Associated Colleges of the Midwest: Costa Rica Field Research Program

January 2011 — May 2011